Guide to the New-York Historical Society Poster Collection 1790-2022 PR 55
New-York Historical Society
- Series IX. Other Subjects, 1896-2021
  - Subseries IX.14. 9/11 (incl posters by Creative Time), 2001-2006
    - "Ground Zero 9/11/01", 2001 (Folder FF 09-20)
      3 copies. Poster is a reprint of a painting of fifefighters at Ground Zero helping an injured person. The painting and the poster are both signed by the artist, Maurice Scherer (?). On back of each copy, "Unsolicited gift, 2015".
    - "Graphics of New York City before September 11, 2001" (Folder FF 09-20)
      Poster and collection created by Jimmy DiResta, "over 100 images and growing". Poster includes several images of business logos using Manhattan skyline with the World Trade Center. On back, "Unsolicited gift, 2015".
    - White poster sheet with twin towers cut out, c.2001 (Folder FF 09-21)
      2 copies. Poster created by Hans Haacke for CreativeTime.
    - Advertisement for town meeting, "Listening to the City. Remember and Rebuild", 2002 (Folder FF 09-20)
      The town meeting was held on July 20, 2002, at the Jacob Javits Center, and was sponsored by the Civic Alliance, convened by Regional Planning Association, to Rebuild Downtown New York.The New-York Historical Society poster features images of Downtown New York from 1664 through 2001.
    - "De-Fuse The Minefield of Anger", 2002 (Folder FF 09-21)
      Poster by the ANTI.BIAS. Squad, students from East Side Community High School, NYC. Sponsored by Time to Consider: The Arts Respond to 9.11. Creative Time, Poets & Writers, Van Alen Institute, and Worldstudio Foundation invited poster submissions for this exhibition, Time to Consider: The Arts Respond to 9.11. Accompanying poster is a small pamphlet on the exhibition.
    - "Life/Death" remote control, 2002 (Folder FF 09-21)
      Poster by Nebojsa Seric Shoba, artist. Sponsored by Time to Consider: The Arts Respond to 9.11. Creative Time, Poets & Writers, Van Alen Institute, and Worldstudio Foundation invited poster submissions for this exhibition, Time to Consider: The Arts Respond to 9.11. Accompanying poster is a small pamphlet on the exhibition.
    - "Contribute a Memory", 2002 (Folder FF 09-21)
      Poster by Eric Lifton, architect. "More memories at www.randomaccessmemorial.org." Sponsored by Time to Consider: The Arts Respond to 9.11. Creative Time, Poets & Writers, Van Alen Institute, and Worldstudio Foundation invited poster submissions for this exhibition, Time to Consider: The Arts Respond to 9.11. Accompanying poster is a small pamphlet on the exhibition.
    - "How The Lurking...", 2002 (Folder FF 09-21)
      Poster and poem by Elena Alexander, November 2001. Sponsored by Time to Consider: The Arts Respond to 9.11. Creative Time, Poets & Writers, Van Alen Institute, and Worldstudio Foundation invited poster submissions for this exhibition, Time to Consider: The Arts Respond to 9.11. Accompanying poster is a small pamphlet on the exhibition.
    - The Twin Towers Logo Project 2001-2006 (Folder FF 09-21)
      Poster created by Phyllis Wrynn, photographs and art direction byb Phyllis Wrynn, assisted by Eric March, and published by Park Slope Gallery. Poster features logos with the twin towers. On accompanying note, "Gift of Linda Ferber, 2019".
  - Subseries IX.15. History Responds collecting: Covid-19 / Social & Racial Justice, 2020
    - "Yellow Peril Supports Black Power", 2020 (Folder OSFF-09-29)
      InkJet Print by Kenn Lam. History Responds Collections Initiative. Gift of the artist, Kenn Lam, 2021.
    - "Apocalyptic Self Care", 2020 (Folder OSFF-09-29)
      Poster by Emma Sasso. History Responds Collections Initiative. Gift of the artist, Emma Sasso, 2021.
    - "No One Is Above The Law (side 1); Stop The GOP Coup (side 2), 2020 (Folder OSFF-09-29)
      History Responds Collections Initiative.
    - "No racism. No fear. Immigrants are welcome here.", 2020 (Folder OSFF-09-29)
      Poster by United Against Racism and Fascism, NYC. History Responds Collections Initiative.
    - "Black Lives Matter", 2020 (Folder OSFF-09-29)
      Black Lives Matter superimposed on sheet with Asian Characters. History Responds Collections Initiative.
    - "New York Tough", 2020 (Folder OSFF-09-29)
      Poster capturing early days of Covid19 in New York with timeline and phases. [Signed?] "Excelsior! Andrew Cuomo". History Responds Collections Initiative.
    - "Black Lives Matter. Download this poster for FREE at: tinyurl.com/ybqvtogn", 2020 (Folder OSFF-09-29)
      Includes names of many whose lives were lost. History Responds Collections Initiative.
  - Subseries IX.16. New York Buildings and Views, 1975-2017
    - The Architectural League of New York's Beaux Arts Tour, 1975 (Folder FF 09-28)
      Featured photograph of the U.S. Customs House Interior by Cervin Robinson. Tour details on backside of poster. Gift of Deborah Nevins.
    - "Grand Central Terminal", [1980's] (Folder FF 09-28)
      Poster designed by Metro-North Commuter Railroad and features architectural plans and details of the terminal.
    - The Style of Long Island: 300 Years of Architecture and the Decorative Arts, 1987 (Folder FF 09-28)
      Poster designed by Joseph del Gaudio Design Group Inc. The chart featuring 117 images of architecture and decorative arts was compiled bby Carolyn Max and Deborah C. Lee with the assistance of others and published by The Society for the Preservation of Long Island Antiquities, as a memorial to their late trustee, Bertha Benkard Rose. On back, in pencil, "Gift of Jean Ashton, July 1987."
    - "Wanted: A Waterfront for New York", 1987 (Folder FF 09-28)
      Poster designed by Anthony Russell, Inc. and photograph of the lower westside of Manhattan's waterfront by Jake Rajs. Poster explains the Idea Competition by the Municipal Art Society for a four mile stretch of waterfront on Manhattan's lower westside.
    - "Fifth Avenue" poster, 1988 (Folder FF 09-28)
      Poster copyrighted by Laurel Arts, Los Angeles; photography by David Yost; Electronic Prepress Response System: Scitex America Corp, Gayle Rosen; printed by Acme Printing Company, Wilmington, MA; accompanying booklet by Steve Marvin. Poster features photographs of the "majestic facade of Fifth Avenue facing Central Park."
    - "Manhattan Municipal Building Seventy-fifth Anniversary, 1914-1989" (Folder FF 09-28)
      Poster designed by CityGraphics. Artwork courtesy of New-York Historical Society. Poster features a reproduction of original ink and watercolor of Municipal Building, c. 1908.
    - "New York City" by Steven Hans Lindner, 2001 (Folder FF 09-28)
      Aerial view of Manhattan, foreground; Bronx, Brooklyn, Queens, background. Copyright by Steven Hans Lindner, 2001.
    - Series of 4 "Rebuild Penn Station" posters, 2017 (Folder FF 09-28)
      "The Station We Deserve" features image of Rebuilt Seventh Avenue Facade by Jeff Stikeman Architectural Art. "Civilized Arrivals" features image of Rebuilt Concourse with Widened Platforms and Tripled Escalators by Jeff Stikeman Architectural Art. "Spaces to Inspire" features image of Rebuilt Main Waiting Room by Jeff Stikeman Architectural Art. "Reasons to Linger." features image of New Covered Arcades on 31st and 33rd Streets by Jeff Stikeman Architectural Art. Sponsors for all posters include the National Civic Art Society, Remains Lighting, Barn Farm Studio, and Atelier & Co. Posters were a gift of Sam Turvey of Rebuild Penn Station, National Civic Art Society.
  - Subseries IX.17. Transportation / Airlines (incl TWA), 1936-1960
    - "2 Days to Europe", 1936 (Folder OSFF-09-33)
      Poster designed by Jupp Wiertz for the Hamburg-American Line-North German Lloyd, General Passenger Agents. Poster features a Hindenburg Zeppelin flying over the Manhattan skyline, specifically over the Empire State Building.
    - "TWA - Service Aerien Rayonnant Sur L'Amerique", ca. 1952 (Folder OSFF-09-33)
      Trans World Airline poster lithographed in U.S.A.
    - "TWA...Save...Fly to America...Sky Tourist Service", ca. 1952 (Folder OSFF-09-33)
      Trans World Airlines poster litho in U.S.A.
    - "Fly TWA New York", 1956 (Folder OSFF-09-33)
      TWA poster designed by David Klein. This poster features a night skyline.
    - "New York...Fly TWA", ca. 1960 (Folder OSFF-09-33)
      Poster designed and signed by David Klein. TWA New York poster features many New York City landmarks, including the Statue of Liberty, St. Patricks, Columbus Circle column. Poster was "Litho in U.S.A."
  - Subseries IX.18. United Nations, 1946
    - "The United Nations for Peace and World Progress", 1946 (Folder OSFF-09-34)
      The poster was printed by the Government Printing Office and was a Department of State publication. The poster features a diagram of the United Nations corporate structure and gives examples of how the United Nations promotes international cooperation. Acquisition date (?) on back, Oct. 31, 1946.
    - "We, the Peoples of the United Nations, have determined...", 1946 (Folder OSFF-09-34)
      The poster was based on the preamble to the United Nations' charter and was published and distributed as a public service by General Mills. On back, the complete preamble is set out. Acquisition date (?) on back, Oct. 31, 1946.
  - Subseries IX.19. Lesbian/Gay/Bisexual/Transgender/Queer (LGBTQ+), 1989-2000
    - Keith Haring - Ignorance=Fear/Silence=Death, 1989 (Folder OSFF-09-31)
      Poster by Keith Haring for Act Up to fight AIDS.
    - "Unfortunately, History Has Set The Record A Little Too Straight.", 1989 (Folder OSFF-09-31)
      Poster designed by Laurie Casagrande. Poster (#P231CW A Little Too Straight) part of "Tools For Change" from Syracuse Cultural Workers (SCW). In support of National Coming Out Day -- poster features images of 10 figures who made their mark on history, regardless of their sexual orientation.
    - "Joan Jett-Blakk For President...By Any Means Necessary", [1992] (Folder OSFF-09-31)
      Published by Imprime:BOCM. Image of Joan Jett-Blakk by Marc Geller. Signed by Joan Jett-Blakk.
    - "Vote on November 7th...come out and into the voting booth" Those Who Have Fallen poster, 2000 (Folder OSFF-09-31)
      Poster published by Gill Operating Foundation to support www.outvote2000.org.
    - "Vote on November 7th...come out and into the voting booth" Make Sure They Know We're Out Here poster, 2000 (Folder OSFF-09-31)
    - "Lesbian Pride", undated (Folder OSFF-09-31)
      No publisher or designer given. Image is of two nudes hugging. Poster is in two colors: purple and orange.